Verle G. Kaiser Papers 1932-1982
Washington State University Libraries: Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC)
- Pacific Northwest, Series 9
  - Plain Line Maps, Trapper Creek, Nez Perce National Forest, undated; 1 item. (Box 18, Folder 1084)
  - Planning for the Water Needs of the Northwest: A Comprehensive Study of the Columbia Region, 1966; 1 item. (Box 18, Folder 1085)
  - Plant Science Handbook, Water and Soil Conservation, 1967; 1 item. (Box 18, Folder 1086)
  - Plant Science Handbook, Water and Soil Conservation, 1968; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1087)
  - Problem Areas in Soil and Water Conservation, Dryland Grainlands: Sample Farm Inventories, 1971-1972; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1088)
  - Problem Areas in Soil and Water Conservation, Dryland Grainlands: Sample Farm Inventories, 1971-1972; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1089)
  - Problems of Environment, Washington State, 1972; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1090)
  - Progress Report on the Economics of Conservation Farming, Pacific Northwest Wheatlands, 1953; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1091)
  - Published Climatological Records of Precipitation, Pacific Northwest, 1931-1969; 32 items. (Box 19, Folder 1092)
  - Resource Inventories and Conservation Treatment Needs for Problem Areas in Dry Cropland, 1972; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1093)
  - Resource Study, Washington State: Warden, Weber, Lind and Providence Watersheds, 1968; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1094)
  - Skagit Valley, Washington, undated; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1095)
  - Soil Conditions, Washington State, 1967; 8 items. (Box 19, Folder 1096)
  - Soil Conservation Section: Papers Read at the Joint Meeting of Northwest Scientific Association and Oregon Academy of Science, 1952; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1097)
  - Some Economic Aspects of Grassland in Kootenai and Benewah Counties, 1963; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1098)
  - Standards for Conservation Treatment, undated; 70 items. (Box 19, Folder 1099)
  - State of Washington: Nez Perce, "Red Eagles of the Northwest", 1939 (Box 19, Folder 1100)
  - St. Joeseph National Forest, Idaho, 1935; 4 items. (Box 19, Folder 1101)
  - Stubble Mulch Problems and Operations, 1959; 19 items. (Box 19, Folder 1102)
  - Stubble Mulch Problems and Operations, 1968; 34 items. (Box 19, Folder 1103)
  - Stubble Agriculture Information Bulletin, 1962; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1104)
  - Technical Guides, Outdated Material, 1954-1960; 24 items. (Box 19, Folder 1105)
  - Technical Guides, Outdated Material, 1959-1962; 23 items. (Box 19, Folder 1106)
  - Technical Guides, Outdated Material, 1964; 30 items. (Box 19, Folder 1107)
  - The Columbia Plateau Region, undated; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1108)
  - The Columbia Resources Council, Information Booklet, undated; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1109)
  - The Columbia River Architectural Firm, undated; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1110)
  - The Importance of Grasses and Legumes in Wheat Production: Eastern Washington, undated; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1111)
  - The Keefer Plan: Its Future for Waterfowl Development and Hunting, undated; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1112)
  - The Nature and Present Use of Conservation Practices Pacific Northwest: Progress Report on the Economics of Conservation, Vol. II, 1953; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1113)
  - The Reasons for and the Place of Field Plantings in the SCS, Idaho, 1965; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1114)
  - The Role of Sprinkler Irrigation in the Development of Irrigated Farms, undated; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1115)
  - The State of Washington: "The Cost of WPPSS On Your Electric Bill", 1982; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1116)
  - The Treaty with Canada for Joint Development of the Columbia River, Handbook, 1965; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1117)
  - The Washington Water Power Company, Annual Report, 1963; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1118)
  - Tour Guide, Area IV, Yakima, Washington, 1968; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1119)
  - Two-Hundred and Eight Dryland Technical Advisory Committee Meeting, Pasco, 1978; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1120)
  - USDA Report on Water and Related Land Resources, John Day River Basin, Oregon, SCS, 1961; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1121)
  - USDA Conservation Planning, Eastern Washington, 1965; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1122)
  - United States Geological Survey Resource Investigations, 1965; 7 items. (Box 19, Folder 1123)
  - "Use Alfalfa to Replace Sweet Clover for Green Manure In Dryland Crop Rotations," Verle G. Kaiser, 1958; 1 item. (Box 19, Folder 1124)
  - Walla Walla County, Washington: Soil and Water Conservation District Work Unit Technical Guide, undated; 2 items. (Box A, Folder 1125-1126)
  - Washington: Legislation to Increase Price Supports for Farmers, undated; 1 item. (Box A, Folder 1127)
  - Washington's Resources, Our Challenge, undated; 1 item. (Box A, Folder 1128)
  - Washington State Centennial, 1853-1953; 1 item. (Box A, Folder 1129)
  - Washington Farm and Home News, "Oxford Economist Calls Population Explosion a Good Thing", 1963; 2 items. (Box A, Folder 1130)
  - Washington Farm and Home News, "Land of Washington", undated; 1 item. (Box A, Folder 1131)
  - Washington State: Methods of Controlling Erosion in the Walla Walla Soil Conservation District, undated; 1 item. (Box A, Folder 1132)
  - Washington State Planning and Community Affairs Agency, "Community Action for Environmental Quality", 1970; 1 item. (Box A, Folder 1133)
  - Washington State: Snake River Tramways, 1962; 2 items. (Box A, Folder 1134)
  - Water Conservation and Management, 1957, 1967; 23 items. (Box A, Folder 1135)
  - Water Pollution Control: The Federal Costs 1969-1973, U.S. Department of Interior Report to Congress, 1968, 1 item. (Box A, Folder 1136)
  - Water Resources Development, Oregon: U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, 1965; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1137)
    - Washington, 1965; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1138)
    - Idaho, 1965; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1139)
  - Water Resources Investigation, Washington, 1965; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1140)
  - Watershed Work Plan, Locke Watershed, Pend Oreille County, Washington, 1965; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1141)
  - Western Water Development: A Summary of Water Resources, Projects, Plans, and Studies by the Committee on Public Works, U.S. Senate, 1964; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1142)
  - "Working with Soil Conservation Districts," Regional Administrative Conference, Oregon, 1949; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1143)
- The Palouse, Series 10
  - Agriculture and Soil Conservation Bulletins and Reports of Columbia Plateau Dryland Agriculture, prior to 1940; 12 items. (Box 20, Folder 1144)
    - Reprints, prior to 1940; 11 items. (Box 20, Folder 1145)
    - Reprints, 1940; 16 items. (Box 20, Folder 1146)
    - Reprints, 1940; 18 items. (Box 20, Folder 1147)
  - Agricultural Sketch of the History of the Palouse River Basin, undated; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1148)
  - Agronomy Workshop, 1956; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1149)
  - Annual Cropping, 1949, 1953; 18 items. (Box 20, Folder 1150)
  - Annual Cropping and Grain Recropping, 1967; 14 items. (Box 20, Folder 1151)
  - Annual Cropping, 1952; 26 items. (Box 20, Folder 1152)
  - Annual Report, Pine Creek Soil Conservation District, Pine Creek, Washington, 1954; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1153)
  - Annual Soil Loss by Water Erosion, Whitman County, 1939-1965; 2 items. (Box 20, Folder 1154)
  - Average Annual Wheat Yields, Whitman County, 1934-1975; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1155)
  - Benewah County, Idaho: U.S. Department of Commerce Census, 1960; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1156)
  - Benton County, Washington, Soils Area: Below Fifteen Inches Precipitation, undated; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1157)
  - Boron and Molybdenum on Legumes, 1939, 1956-1957; 3 items. (Box 20, Folder 1158)
  - Branch Line of the Northern Pacific in Colfax, "Bunchgrass Pioneer," by Joe Smith, undated; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1159)
  - Brooks-Hensley Architects Design of Pullman and W.S.U., undated; 3 items. (Box 20, Folder 1160)
  - "Bunchgrass Pioneer," from Stock-Raising to Wheat Raising in the Palouse, by Joe Smith, 1971; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1161)
  - "Bunchgrass Pioneer", undated; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1162)
  - Central Whitman Soil Conservation District: Summary Reports, Stubble Mulch Trials, by Verle Kaiser, 1946-1947; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1163)
  - Cheatgrass Control, Palouse and Eastern Washington, 1963; 23 items. (Box 20, Folder 1164)
  - Cheatgrass Control, 1969-1970; 39 items. (Box 20, Folder 1165)
  - City of Colville, Letter from City Planner Gregory Moore, 1979; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1166)
  - Clearwater Power Dam, Idaho: Silting, undated; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1167)
  - Climate of the Palouse, Idaho and Washington, 1965; 2 items. (Box 20, Folder 1168)
  - Columbia County Soil Survey Handbook, 1949
    - Pages 1-50, 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1169)
    - Pages 51-93, 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1170)
  - Columbia Snake Palouse Environmental Program, 1966, 1971; 6 items. (Box 20, Folder 1171)
  - Comparison of Precipitation: Soil Erosion, Wheat Yields, Whitman County, Washington, 1933-1971; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1172)
  - Comparison of Precipitation: Soil Erosion, Wheat Yields, Whitman County, Washington, 1933-1977; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1173)
  - Comparison of Precipitation: Soil Erosion, Wheat Yields, Whitman County, Washington, 1969; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1174)
  - Conditions Leading to Runoff in Whitman County, 1970-1971; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1175)
  - "Conservation Cropping Systems for the Palouse," by Verle Kaiser, 1963; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1176)
  - Conservation Plan
    - Irma Pritchard Farm, South Palouse, 1947; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1177)
    - John Doe Farm, South Palouse, undated; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1178)
    - Ranch Land, Palouse and Pine Creek Districts, 1950; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1179)
  - Conservation Treatment, Whitman County, 1972; 2 items. (Box 20, Folder 1180)
  - Contract Papers, 1976; 13 items. (Box 20, Folder 1181)
  - Co-operative River Basin Study, undated; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1182)
  - Co-operative River Basic Study, undated; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1183)
  - County Soils Within the Palouse: Capability Studies, 1964-1966; 14 items. (Box 20, Folder 1184)
  - Crop Enterprise Budgets for the Eastern Palouse, Washington, 1980; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1185)
  - Crop Residues and Residue Utilization, 1978; 14 items. (Box 20, Folder 1186)
    - Rotations, 1961; 3 items. (Box 20, Folder 1187)
  - Cropping History, Gonos Schulthois Ranch, 1976-1978; 7 items. (Box 20, Folder 1188)
  - Curlew Region: Self Help Action to Reduce Unemployment, 1950-1980; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1189)
  - Description of Mapping Units, Palouse Series, undated; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1190)
  - Draft Implementation Proposal for Conservation Resource Management Systems, Pleasant Valley Creek Watershed, 1980; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1191)
  - Early Pioneers of the Thornton Area, by Mrs. Dale Curtis and Mrs. Edgar Kerns, undated; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1192)
  - Early Roads: Report of Captain John Mullan, 1859-1860; 3 items. (Box 20, Folder 1193)
  - Economic Returns for Different Cropping Systems, Palouse and Athena Soils, 1958-1959; 2 items. (Box 20, Folder 1194)
  - Economics of Cropping Systems and Soil Conservation in the Palouse, 1961; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1195)
  - Effect of Grass on Erosion and Grain Yields in the Palouse, 1978; 14 items. (Box 20, Folder 1196)
    - On Soil Rotation Following Grain Yields, 1978; 3 items. (Box 20, Folder 1197)
  - Engineering Performance Survey for South Palouse Soil Conservation Project, pp. 1-61, 1940; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1198)
  - Engineering Performance Survey for South Palouse Soil Conservation Project, pp. 61-114, 1940; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1199)
  - Environmental Conservation Program, undated; 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1200)
  - Erosion and Crop Protection, undated; 16 items. (Box 21, Folder 1201)
  - Erosion Control Project, Pleasant Valley Watershed, 1978-1979; 19 items. (Box 21, Folder 1202)
  - Establishment of Sweet Clover, 1945-1952; 7 items. (Box 21, Folder 1203)
  - Evaluation Areas: Comparison of New and Old Soil Surveys, 1970; 10 items. (Box 21, Folder 1204)
  - Excerpts from a Pine Creek Soil Conservation District Newsletter, 1959; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1205)
  - Extension Plan Outside Moscow, Idaho, SCS, 1938; 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1206)
  - Facts about the Sieveke Farm, Tekoa, Washington, undated; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1207)
  - Farm Management and Economic Survey Report for South Fork of the Palouse River, pp. 1-150, 1933-1935; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1208)
  - Farm Management and Economic Survey Report for South Fork of the Palouse River, pp. 51-76, 1933-1935; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1209)
  - Farm Planners' Handbook, Palouse, 1942; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1210)
    - Sections A-D, 1944; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1211)
    - Sections A-K, 1944; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1212)
    - Sections A-D, 1945; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1213)
    - Sections D-K, 1945; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1214)
    - Sections A-E, 1952; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1215)
    - Sections E-K, 1952; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1216)
  - Farm Planning Schools: Leader's Outline and Reference Materials, undated; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1217)
  - Farmington, Pioneers of, 1971; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1218)
  - Fertilizers: Effect on Soil Structure, 1955; 10 items. (Box 21, Folder 1219)
  - Field Trials and Demonstrations Conducted in Whitman County: Wheat Yields and their Maintenance, 1955; 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1220)
  - Geology of the Palouse Region, 1940, 1968; 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1221)
  - Grain Production, 1933-1980; 14 items. (Box 21, Folder 1222)
  - Grainland Agriculture, western Whitman County Washington, 1943; 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1223)
  - Greater Palouse CNI Basic Data, Idaho and Oregon, 1971; 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 1224-1225)
  - Growing Sweet Clover in Latah County, by O.S. Fletcher, 1923; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1226)
  - Help Available to Whitman County Schoolteachers from the SCS, 1955; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1227)
  - "Hindsight and Foresight," by Verle Kaiser for the SCS, 1954; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1228)
  - Historical Background to the Steptoe Butte, undated; 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 1229)
  - "Historical Land Use and Erosion in the Palouse," A Reappraisal," by Verle Kaiser, 1952; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1230)
  - Index to County Quadrangles, 1972; 37 items. (Box 21, Folder 1231)
  - "Influence of Past Farming Methods on Erosion and Crop Production for Two Palouse Farms," by Verle Kaiser, 1950; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1232)
  - Informal Report of Social and Water Conservation Educational Activities in Public Schools, Whitman County, 1949-1949; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1233)
  - Information About Original Land Survey of Whitman County, undated; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1234)
  - Kenneth Abbey Farm, East Benton, undated; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1235)
  - King Wheat and His Palouse Empire, undated; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1236)
  - "Lab Open for Business", undated; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1237)
  - Land Capability: Distribution of Major Soils and their Capabilities, Palouse, undated; 5 items. (Box 21, Folder 1238)
  - Land Use Capability Chart, North Palouse Soil Conservation Project, undated; 14 items. (Box 21, Folder 1239)
  - Latah County, Idaho: Soil Survey Handbook, undated; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1240)
  - Latah-Rock Creek Soil Conservation District, 1940-1945; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1241)
  - Latah Soil Conservation District, 1941; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1242)
  - Legumes and Alfalfa, Palouse, undated; 28 items. (Box 21, Folder 1243)
  - Letter: Inland Power and Light Company, 1982; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1244)
  - Letters: Palouse Allotment Program and its Effect on Soil Conservation, between Verle Kaiser and Representative Thomas Foley, 1977-1978; 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1245)
  - Machinery and Stubble Problems in the Palouse, undated; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1246)
  - Major Problems for Soil and Water Conservation in Dryland Grainlands of Columbia-Snake-Palouse Area, 1972; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1247)
  - Major Soil Association Data, 1961; 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 1248)
  - Map: Approximate Distribution of Major Soil Series, Whitman County, Washington, 1943; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1249)
  - Matrix for Palouse Maps, 1934, 1980, 1981; 20 items. (Box 21, Folder 1250)
  - Methods of Soil Conservation, 1943-1945; 20 items. (Box 21, Folder 1251)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Hustle Hollow Supervisors, 1946; 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 1252)
  - Miscellaneous Material, 1951-1979; 14 items. (Box 21, Folder 1253)
  - Multilitheel Work Copies, Early Palouse History, 1937-1968; 7 items. (Box 21, Folder 1254)
  - New Low-Cost Source of Sulfur Fertilizer to be Demonstrated, 1965; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1255)
  - Nitrogen Fertilizer Trials, South Palouse-Pine Creek, 1944-1945; 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1256)
  - Nitrogen Fertilizer Trials, South Palouse-Pine Creek, 1945; 5 items. (Box 22, Folder 1257)
  - Nitrogen Fertilizer Trials, South Palouse-Pine Creek, 1946; 16 items. (Box 22, Folder 1258)
  - Nitrogen Fertilizer Trials, South Palouse-Pine Creek, 1947; 21 items. (Box 22, Folder 1259)
  - Nitrogen Fertilizer Trials, South Palouse-Pine Creek, 1948; 15 items. (Box 22, Folder 1260)
  - Nitrogen Fertilizer Trials, South Palouse-Pine Creek, 1950-1951; 8 items. (Box 22, Folder 1261)
  - Nitrogen Fertilizer Trials, South Palouse-Pine Creek, 1952; 34 items. (Box 22, Folder 1262)
  - Nitrogen Fertilizer Trials, South Palouse-Pine Creek, 1953; 33 items. (Box 22, Folder 1263)
  - Nitrogen Fertilizer Trials, South Palouse-Pine Creek, 1954-1955; 4 items. (Box 22, Folder 1264)
  - Nitrogen/Moisture Testing for Wheat-Crop, South Palouse, 1953-1968; 23 items. (Box 22, Folder 1265)
  - Nitrogen on Grain Crops, 1937-1966; 28 items. (Box 22, Folder 1266)
  - No-Till Farming, 1980; 10 items. (Box 22, Folder 1267)
  - North Palouse Soil Conservation District, Pfaff Farm, undated; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1268)
  - Note by Verle Kaiser on Grass Seeding Palouse Hillsides, undated; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1269)
  - Notes on Contour Strip Cropping and Diversion Terraces as Conservation Practices, 1963; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1270)
    - Performance of Different Legumes Seeded in 1958 and Utilized in 1959 for Soil Improvement, Palouse, 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1271)
  - "Of Yesterday and The River," by June Crithfield, undated; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1272)
  - Original Draft: Palouse River Report, by Verle Kaiser, 1977; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1273)
    - Wheat Yield Data, Correlated to Soils, 1938; 5 items. (Box 22, Folder 1274)
  - Palouse and Pacific Northwest: Record of Grain Recropping, 1948-1981; 20 items. (Box 22, Folder 1275)
  - Palouse Conservation Field Station, Annual Report, 1966; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1276)
  - Palouse Country, County Maps, 1960; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1277)
  - Palouse Farmers' Seventh Annual Tour: Specimens of Field Cover That Have Worked, 1940; 4 items. (Box 22, Folder 1278)
  - Palouse Hills Farm Project, Friends of the Farm, 1979-1980; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 1279)
  - Palouse Program Proposal, 1981; 5 items. (Box 22, Folder 1280)
  - Palouse Region Environment and Conservation Committee Meeting, 1970; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1281)
  - Palouse River Drainage, Washington: Problems and Capacity, undated; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1282)
  - Palouse-Rock Lake Soil Conservation District, M.S. Oakes Farm, 1944-1945; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1283)
  - Palouse Problem Areas A and B, Whitman County, undated; 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 1284)
  - Palouse Silt Loam: Its Characteristics and Management, 1959; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1285)
  - Palouse Silt Loam: Its Characteristics and Management, 1961; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 1286)
  - Palouse SCD Plan of Conservation Operations, 1946; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1287)
  - Palouse Soil: Description of and Variation in Land Conditions, 1942; 97 items. (Box 22, Folder 1288)
  - Palouse Tour, SCSA, 1925; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 1289)
  - Pine Creek Soil Conservation District, Whitman County, 1944; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1290)
  - Pine Creek Soil Conservation District, Whitman County, undated; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1291)
  - Plans for Forage Seeding Trails, North Palouse, undated; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1292)
  - Plant Material Center, Airport Road, Pullman, undated; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1293)
  - Plant Materials Guide for Conservation Farming in the Palouse, 1961; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1294)
  - Pointers on Seeding Grasses in the Horse Heaven and Rattlesnake Hills Areas for Conservation, undated; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1295)
  - Policies, Nitrogen and Moisture Testing in the Palouse, 1956; 35 items. (Box 22, Folder 1296)
  - Preliminary Draft, Origin of Palouse Soil, 1975; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1297)
  - Previous History of Perennial Noxious Weed Control in the Palouse, by Verle Kaiser, 1960; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1298)
  - Principles of Water Conservation Runoff and Control, 1964; 6 items. (Box 22, Folder 1299)
  - Project Monograph: South Fork of the Palouse, 1940; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1300)
  - Proposed Conservation Program, 1947; 8 items. (Box 22, Folder 1301)
    - 1976, 20 items. (Box 22, Folder 1302)
    - H.R. 6713, 1971; 28 items. (Box 22, Folder 1303)
    - Plan for Rotation Studies, 1940; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1304)
  - Rebuilding Palouse Subsoil, 1951-1962; 10 items. (Box 22, Folder 1305)
  - Recollections of the Early Settlers, undated; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1306)
  - Reconnaissance, Palouse Area: Field Book, 1936-1980; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1307)
  - Recropping Records, Dorman and Olson Farms, Pullman, 1948; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1308)
  - Reduced Scale Copies, Quadrangle Maps, undated; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1309)
  - Report of Agronomic Work, SCS, South Fork of the Palouse, 1934-1939; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1310)
  - Report of Field Examination, South Fork of the Palouse Watershed, 1957; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1311)
  - Report on Evaluation of Soil Conservation Practices in in the Palouse, 1948; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 1312)
  - Report to the Laboratory Committee, Pine Creek SCS, 1954-1955; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1313)
  - Report: Technical Conferences and Programs, 1953; 14 items. (Box 22, Folder 1314)
  - Report: Technical Conferences and Programs, 1968; 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 1315)
  - Report: Technical Conferences and Programs, undated; 6 items. (Box 22, Folder 1316)
  - Research Field Trials: Basin Information, 1934-1975; 18 items. (Box 22, Folder 1317)
  - Research Field Trials: Basin Information, 1946-1959; 10 items. (Box 22, Folder 1318)
  - Research Field Trials: Basin Information, 1926-1943; 10 items. (Box 22, Folder 1319)
  - Resource Conservation and Development Program, Palouse Region, 1968; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1320)
  - Retracing the 1811 Trek of David Thompson from the Snake River to Spokane House, 1976; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 1321)
  - River Basin Survey, Palouse, 1975; 6 items. (Box 23, Folder 1322)
    - 1977, 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1323)
    - Aggregate Data, undated; 5 items. (Box 23, Folder 1324)
    - Basic Steps in Organizing the Proposed "Columbia-Snake-Palouse Environmental Program", 1969-1970; 36 items. (Box 23, Folder 1325)
    - Basic Steps in Organizing the Proposed "Columbia-Snake-Palouse Environmental Program", 1969-1980; 37 items. (Box 23, Folder 1326)
    - Basic Steps in Organizing the Proposed "Columbia-Snake-Palouse Environmental Program", 1969-1980; 36 items. (Box 23, Folder 1327)
  - Schultheis Ranch Soil Testing, 1978; 13 items. (Box 23, Folder 1328)
  - SCSA Palouse Tour, 1981; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1329)
  - Soil Analysis, Palouse, 1980; 14 items. (Box 23, Folder 1330)
  - Soil and Conservation Society of America Palouse Tour, 1981; 5 items. (Box 23, Folder 1331)
  - Soil and Water Conservation District Newsletter: Pine Creek Annual District Day Meeting, 1962; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1332)
  - Soil and Water Conservation in the Palouse, 1964; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1333)